Dmytro Kryvokhyzha, Ph.D.

Bioinformatics and genomics scientist

8 years of experience. Specialist in the development of pipelines for genomic and transcriptomic data analyses. Driven by solving biological problems with computational tools and enjoy working with large scale data. Seeking to leverage my passion and expertise to help develop automated analyses in an industrial or academic setting.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher, Uppsala University, Sweden

Project: Genomics of diet adaptation in dogs

June 2018 – present

- Analyzed SNPs, structural variants, and RNA-Seq data.
- Integrated the results to find candidate genes underling metabolic adaptations.

Ph.D. student, Uppsala University, Sweden

Project: Genome evolution in an allopolyploid plant species

November 2013 - April 2018

- Performed comparative genomics and population genomics analyses of a hybrid polyploid species and its parental species.
- Published 4 scientific papers.

Visiting student, Harvard University, USA

Project: Hybridization between distantly related tropical butterflies March – July 2013

- Analyzed whole-genome patterns of divergence between species.
- · Wrote a Master's thesis.

Research assistant, Max Plank Institute for Evol. Biol., Germany

Project: Gene expression in different organs of an invasive fish

September 2012 - February 2013

- Analyzed microarray gene expression data.
- Evaluated different microarray data normalization procedures with RNA-Seq data.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Evolutionary Functional Genomics, Uppsala University, Sweden 2013-2018

M.Sc., Erasmus Mundus Master Program in Evolutionary Biology (Uppsala University, University of Montpellier II, Harvard University) 2011 – 2013

M.Sc. & B.Sc. in Biology, Kharkiv National University, Ukraine. 2005 – 2010

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Reproducibility and Data Reuse in Life Science, Uppsala 19 September 2019

Sustainable Software Development (CodeRefinery), Stockholm 25 – 27 March 2019

Introduction & Fundamentals of Data Science, Uppsala

September 2017 - January 2018

CONTACT

E-mail: dmytro.kryvokhyzha@evobio.eu

Phone: +46(0)18-471-4903

Web: evodify.com

GitHub: github.com/evodify

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/evodify

SKILLS

Analyses

- · NGS data processing
- · Population genetics
- · Comparative genomics
- · Functional genomics
- Gene expression

Programming

- Python
- R
- Bash
- AWK
- Scala

Tools

- R Makrdown
- Jupyter
- Git
- Snakemake
- Conda
- Docker

LANGUAGES

- English (fluent)
- · Ukrainian (native)
- · Russian (native)
- · Swedish (beginner)